Guide to the James E. Jackson Audiotapes Collection OH.057
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
James E. Jackson Audiotapes Collection
1960s-1980s
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Jackson, James E., 1914-2007
Jackson, Esther Cooper
OH.057
373 items
James E. Jackson (1914-2007) was an African American communist and civil rights activist, best known for his role in founding and leading the Southern Negro Youth Congress (1937-1948). He was head of the Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA) Louisiana state organization in 1946, and was a Party organizer in the automobile industry in Detroit from 1947-50. He then moved to New York, becoming the Southern Director for the Communist Party. In 1951 he was indicted under the Smith Act (charged with advocating the overthrow of the government), and became a fugitive until 1955. He later served as the Communist Party's Educational Director and as International Affairs Secretary, retiring in 1991. The collection contains recordings of lectures and speeches given by Jackson, as well as talks by other Party leaders, including Gus Hall and Henry Winston.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by James Jackson and Esther Cooper Jackson in 2006.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged into four series: Series I: Biography
Series II: Lectures and Speeches
Series III: Speeches by Others
Series IV: 7 inch reel of 1/4 inch-wide Recording Tapes
Historical/Biographical Note
James E. Jackson (1914-2007) was an African American communist and civil rights activist, best known for his role in founding and leading the Southern Negro Youth Congress (1937-1948). Raised in Richmond, Virginia, Jackson graduated from Virginia Union University in 1934, and at Howard University (the alma mater of his parents) graduated from the College of Pharmacy in 1937. He joined the Communist Party in 1931, and met his future wife Esther Cooper in 1939 (they married in 1941) when Jackson was staying at Fisk while working for Ralph Bunche as an investigator for what would become Gunnar Myrdal's An American Dilemma: The Negro Problem and Modern Democracy (1944).
The Southern Negro Youth Congress, a communist-led popular front organization, conceived at the first National Negro Congress in 1936, held its first annual conference, organized by James Jackson and Ed Strong, in Richmond, in February, 1937. Jackson played a leading role throughout the SNYC's first decade, as indicated by its letterhead from 1946, where Esther Cooper is the Executive Secretary, Jackson the Special Projects Director, and their fellow-communists and close friends Louis and Dorothy Burnham were, respectively, Organizational Secretary and Educational Director. In 1938 Jackson helped lead the successful organizing of the United Tobacco Stemmers and Laborers Union Local 279 in Richmond. In 1939 the SNYC moved is headquarters to Birmingham, Alabama, with its large concentration of African American industrial workers. Under is slogan "Freedom, Equality, Opportunity," the SNYC campaigned for the full range civil, economic, political, and social rights for African Americans. Activities and issues included, in addition to supporting labor organizing (including domestic workers), campaigns against lynching, police brutality and the poll tax, for the right to vote and an end to segregation, for an end to employment discrimination (sometimes via consumer boycotts), and during World War II, for enforcement of the U.S. Fair Employment Practices Committee's resolution 8802 barring discrimination in war industries. The SNYC also published the periodical Cavalcade: The March of Southern Youth, and supported educational and cultural activities, including "People's Theaters." The SNYC held its last conference in 1948, and the pressure of Cold War anti-communism led to its subsequent dissolution. However, SNYC members went on to play important roles in the civil rights movement of the 19650s-60s, including E.D. Nixon, and several became elected officials.
Jackson entered the army in 1943 and served in the Burma theatre for some eighteen months, attainting the rank of sergeant. In 1946 Jackson became State Chairman of the Communist Party of Louisiana. In 1947 the Jacksons moved to Detroit, where they shared a house with future Detroit mayor Coleman Young, and where James Jackson began work as a Party organizer among the autoworkers, while Esther Cooper Jackson was active in the local branches of the Progressive Party and of the Civil Rights Congress, another popular front organization. In 1951 the Jacksons moved to New York and James was named Southern Director of the Communist Party. Later that year he was indicted under the Smith Act (charged with advocating the overthrow of the U.S. government) and went underground to avoid arrest. Emerging five years later, Jackson was sentenced to prison, although he did not serve time as the Smith Act was declared unconstitutional by the Supreme Court.
Thereafter, James Jackson served as a full-time Party official, including as a member of its leading Political Bureau, and as Education Director and as International Affairs Secretary, in which capacity he traveled throughout the Communist countries and elsewhere. James Jackson retired in 1991, in the aftermath of the 1991 split in the CPUSA.
Scope and Contents note
Contains 373 recordings of lectures and speeches, often of an educational nature, given by Jackson, usually at Communist Party forums. There are also some thirty recordings of talks by other Party leaders, including Gus Hall and Henry Winston, a recording of an event celebrating Jackson's 60th birthday, and an interview with Jackson by his daughter, Kathy.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials that have not been preserved and are not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. This process takes several weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Audiocassettes.; Winston, Henry, 1911-1986.; Hall, Gus; Jackson, James E., 1914-2007; Jackson, James E., 1914-2007; Jackson, Esther Cooper; Jackson, Esther Cooper
- Series I: Biography, 453010
  - 60th Birthday Celebration, ca.1967; cuid13674; 453014 (Cassette 1)
  - Side 1: 60th Birthday Celebration - J. Jackson's Speech; Side 2: Unknown Speaker On Middle East, 1974; cuid13675; 453013 (Cassette 2)
  - Esther Cooper Jackson and James Jackson talk about themselves, Undated; cuid13676; 453012 (Cassette 3)
  - Kathy Interviews Jack, Apr 1984; cuid13677; 453011 (Cassette 2)
- Series II: Lectures, Speeches, 452677
  - 125th Anniversary of the Communist Manifesto, 1973; cuid13678; 453009 (Cassette 5)
  - Africa at Audubon Hall, Undated; cuid13679; 453008 (Cassette 6)
  - Afro-American / Black Equality, Aug 1977; cuid13680; 453007 (Cassette 7)
  - Afro-American Conference, Oct 1990; cuid13681; 453006 (Cassette 8)
  - Side 1: Afro-American History / Monthly Series; Side 2: Overview of Black History, 1987; cuid13682; 453005 (Cassette 9)
  - Analysis of News, Undated; cuid13683; 453004 (Cassette 10)
  - On Anti-Sovietism; 23rd Convention, Communist Party, U.S.A., Nov 1983; cuid13684; 453003 (Cassette 11)
  - Side 1: On Anti-Sovietism Report of Jane Gloria; Side 2: Evaluation Report of Comrade Joe, Undated; cuid13685; 453002 (Cassette 12)
  - Black Liberation (1), Mar 1977; cuid13686; 453001 (Cassette 13)
  - Black Liberation (2), Mar 1977; cuid13687; 453000 (Cassette 14)
  - Black Liberation (3), Mar 1977; cuid13688; 452999 (Cassette 15)
  - Black Liberation (4), Mar 1977; cuid13689; 452998 (Cassette 16)
  - Black History in the U.S.A., Undated; cuid13690; 452997 (Cassette 17)
  - Side 1: The Bottom Line; Side 2: The Party, Apr 1977; cuid13691; 452996 (Cassette 18)
  - On Brezhnev's Visit to India and The Polish Crisis and Polish Crisis, Oct 1980; cuid13692; 452995 (Cassette 19)
  - Brussels Conference: Side 1: P.B. Discussion; Side 2: Summary and Motion by James Jackson, Dec 1979; cuid13693; 452994 (Cassette 20)
  - Brussels Conference: Side 1: J. Jackson; Side 2: Discussion, Dec 1979; cuid13694; 452993 (Cassette 21)
  - Capitalism (2), Undated; cuid13695; 452992 (Cassette 22)
  - On Capitalism (3), Undated; cuid13696; 452991 (Cassette 23)
  - Capitalism (3)National School, Mar 1977; cuid13697; 452990 (Cassette 24)
  - Capitalism and Communism, Jun 1976; cuid13698; 452989 (Cassette 25)
  - Chicago Rally 63rd Anniversary C.P.U.S.A., Oct 1982; cuid13699; 452988 (Cassette 26)
  - Chicano Liberation (7-8), Undated; cuid13700; 452987 (Cassette 27)
  - China, Jul 1988; cuid13701; 452986 (Cassette 28)
  - On China, Jun 1989; cuid13702; 452985 (Cassette 29)
  - Classes and the State (1)[Side 1 Starts with: Report on Lenin], Jun 1989; cuid13703; 452984 (Cassette 30)
  - Classes and the State (2), Mar 1977; cuid13704; 452983 (Cassette 31)
  - Classes and State (3), Mar 1977; cuid13705; 452982 (Cassette 32)
  - Classes and State (4), Mar 1977; cuid13706; 452981 (Cassette 33)
  - Class Graduation, Jul 1974; cuid13707; 452980 (Cassette 34)
  - The Class Struggle; Historical Materialism, Q and A's, Undated; cuid13708; 452979 (Cassette 35)
  - The Class Struggle in History (1), May 1981; cuid13709; 452978 (Cassette 36)
  - Club Problems - Centralism and Leadership; Mesaba School, Aug 1977; cuid13710; 452977 (Cassette 37)
  - Side 1: Coalition Politics; Side 2: Socialism, Undated; cuid13711; 452976 (Cassette 38)
  - Color Purple; C.C. Meeting, Jan 1986; cuid13712; 452975 (Cassette 39)
  - Commodity Production (1)National School, Mar 1977; cuid13713; 452974 (Cassette 40)
  - Commodity Production (2)National School, Mar 1977; cuid13714; 452973 (Cassette 41)
  - Commodity Production (3)National School, Mar 1977; cuid13715; 452972 (Cassette 42)
  - Commodity Production / Crisis of Capitalism (4)National School, Mar 1977; cuid13716; 452971 (Cassette 43)
  - Communist Morality (1), Aug 1977; cuid13717; 452970 (Cassette 44)
  - Communist Morality (2), Aug 1977; cuid13718; 452969 (Cassette 45)
  - The Communist Party, May 1981; cuid13719; 452968 (Cassette 46)
  - On the Communist Party (5), Undated; cuid13720; 452967 (Cassette 47)
  - [Communist Party] Side 1: 1st Main Political Report (Weinstein, D.); Side 2: 2nd Main Political Report (Jackson, J.), Undated; cuid13721; 452966 (Cassette 48)
  - Communist Party, C.C. Meeting; 60th Anniversary of the Soviet Union, Dec 1977; cuid13722; 452965 (Cassette 49)
  - [Communist Party], C.C. Meeting; 60th Anniversary of the Soviet Union (6), Dec 1977; cuid13723; 452964 (Cassette 50)
  - [Communist Party], C.C. Meeting; 60th Anniversary of the Soviet Union (8), Dec 1977; cuid13724; 452963 (Cassette 51)
  - Communist Party, C.C. Meeting; 60th Anniversary of the Soviet Union, Dec 1977; cuid13725; 452962 (Cassette 52)
  - Communist Party, Plenary Meeting; 60th Anniversary of the Soviet Union, Dec 1977; cuid13726; 452961 (Cassette 53)
  - Communist Party, 63rd Anniversary, Chicago, Sep 1984; cuid13727; 452960 (Cassette 54)
  - Communist Party, 66th Anniversary, Detroit, MI, Sep 1985; cuid13728; 452959 (Cassette 55)
  - Communist Party, 22nd Convention, Aug 1979; cuid13729; 452958 (Cassette 56)
  - [Communist Party]23rd Convention, Cleveland, OH, Nov 1983; cuid13730; 452957 (Cassette 57)
  - Communist Party, Plenary Meeting (4)23rd Convention, Nov 10, 1983-Nov 13, 1983; cuid13731; 452956 (Cassette 58)
  - Communist Party Plenary Meeting (5)23rd Convention, Nov 1983; cuid13732; 452955 (Cassette 59)
  - Communist Party, Plenary Meeting (6)23rd Convention, Plenary Meeting, Nov 1983; cuid13733; 452954 (Cassette 60)
  - Communist Party24th Convention, Chicago, IL, 1987; cuid13734; 452953 (Cassette 61)
  - [Communist Party]C.C. Meeting (?), Feb 1975; cuid13735; 452952 (Cassette 62)
  - Communist Party; C.C. Meeting, Jun 1979; cuid13736; 452951 (Cassette 63)
  - [Communist Party], C.C. Meeting - Peace, Apr 1983; cuid13737; 452950 (Cassette 64)
  - Communist Party National Committee Meeting, Aug 1990; cuid13738; 452949 (Cassette 65)
  - [Communist Party] National Committee, Jan 1981; cuid13739; 452948 (Cassette 66)
  - [Communist Party] Plenary Session on Functioning, Feb 1975; cuid13740; 452947 (Cassette 67)
  - Conference on Communism, Undated; cuid13741; 452946 (Cassette 68)
  - Conference on Communism, Socialism, Capitalism, Undated; cuid13742; 452945 (Cassette 69)
  - Correlation of Theory and Policy, May 1979; cuid13743; 452944 (Cassette 70)
  - Cultural Principles (Mesaba School), Aug 1977; cuid13744; 452943 (Cassette 71)
  - The Decade of 1890's, Undated; cuid13745; 452942 (Cassette 72)
  - Side 1: The Decade of 1890's; Side 2: C.C. On Peace, Undated; cuid13746; 452941 (Cassette 73)
  - Detante (1), Undated; cuid13747; 452940 (Cassette 74)
  - Detante (2), Undated; cuid13748; 452939 (Cassette 75)
  - Dialectical and Historical Materialism (3), Feb 1975; cuid13749; 452938 (Cassette 76)
  - Dialectical Laws and Categories, Jan 1975; cuid13750; 452937 (Cassette 77)
  - Dialectical Materialism (1), Undated; cuid13751; 452936 (Cassette 78)
  - Side 1: Dialectical Materialism; Side 2: Discussion, Undated; cuid13752; 452935 (Cassette 79)
  - Side 1: Dialectical Materialism + Philosophy; Side 2: Dialectical Production, Undated; cuid13753; 452934 (Cassette 80)
  - Dialectical Materialism, Jul 1978; cuid13754; 452933 (Cassette 81)
  - Side 1: Dielectical Materialism; Side 2: Historical Materialism, Dec 1975; cuid13755; 452932 (Cassette 82)
  - Dialectical Materialism East Coast Regional School, Jul 1978; cuid13756; 452931 (Cassette 83)
  - Dialectical Materialism (1) What is Philosophy?, Jul 1978; cuid13757; 452930 (Cassette 84)
  - Side 1: Dialectics; Side 2: Dialectics, Ethics, Dec 1975; cuid13758; 452929 (Cassette 85)
  - Dialectics and Materialism, Undated; cuid13759; 452928 (Cassette 86)
  - Dialectics and Materialism, Jan 1976; cuid13760; 452927 (Cassette 87)
  - Discussion, Undated; cuid13761; 452926 (Cassette 88)
  - Discussion (3), Mar 1975; cuid13762; 452925 (Cassette 89)
  - Discussion on the Soviet Union, Undated; cuid13763; 452924 (Cassette 90)
  - Side 1: Discussion - Jim Jackson Black Question + C.P. - Ted Bassett; Side 2: Evolution of Black Policy - Ted Bassett, Undated; cuid13764; 452923 (Cassette 91)
  - Discussion (J. Jackson, D. Weinstein, R. Storey), Undated; cuid13765; 452922 (Cassette 92)
  - Side 1: Discussion + Report; Side 2: Lecture on Social Revolution, Undated; cuid13766; 452921 (Cassette 93)
  - Discussion / Political Economy: Value, Price, Profit, Aug 1977; cuid13767; 452920 (Cassette 94)
  - Side 1: Discussion; Side 2: Imperialism (Stages of), Mar 2, 1978-Mar 6, 1978; cuid13768; 452919 (Cassette 95)
  - Discussion, Update, Aug 1988; cuid13769; 452918 (Cassette 96)
  - Du Bois - Foster School Graduation, Apr 1977; cuid13770; 452917 (Cassette 97)
  - Election, 1984; cuid13771; 452916 (Cassette 98)
  - Side 1: Entertainment Industry / Blacks; Side 2: Class Struggle / Capitalism, Undated; cuid13772; 452915 (Cassette 99)
  - Side 1: Ethics; Side 2: Philosophy / Moral Mission, Undated; cuid13773; 452914 (Cassette 100)
  - Ethics (2), Dec 1975; cuid13774; 452913 (Cassette 101)
  - Ethiopian Revolution, Mar 1978; cuid13775; 452912 (Cassette 102)
  - Evaluations, Undated; cuid13776; 452911 (Cassette 103)
  - Evaluations 4/15, Undated; cuid13777; 452910 (Cassette 104)
  - Evaluations, Aug 1976; cuid13778; 452909 (Cassette 105)
  - Side 1: Falsifiers of Marxism (with Victor Perlo); Side 2: Ideological Falsifiers, Mar 1976; cuid13779; 452908 (Cassette 106)
  - FBI 000-222 - J. Jackson's Spec. Put, Undated; cuid13780; 452907 (Cassette 107)
  - De Maio Discussion (?) - Jackson, Jim, Undated; cuid13781; 452906 (Cassette 108)
  - France Electorial, Mar 1973; cuid13782; 452905 (Cassette 109)
  - Group Evaluations (tape broken), Apr 1977; cuid13783; 452904 (Cassette 110)
  - Group Evaluations and Remarks, Apr 1977; cuid13784; 452903 (Cassette 111)
  - Henry Winston Memorial Meeting (1), Jan 1987; cuid13785; 452902 (Cassette 112)
  - Henry Winston Memorial Meeting (2), Jan 1987; cuid13786; 452901 (Cassette 113)
  - Historical Materialism, Undated; cuid13787; 452900 (Cassette 114)
  - Historical Materialism, Undated; cuid13788; 452899 (Cassette 115)
  - Historical Materialism (1), Undated; cuid13789; 452898 (Cassette 116)
  - Historical Materialism (2), Undated; cuid13790; 452897 (Cassette 117)
  - Historical Materialism (3-4), Undated; cuid13791; 452896 (Cassette 118)
  - Historical Materialism (5-6), Undated; cuid13792; 452895 (Cassette 119)
  - Historical Materialism, Discussion on, Undated; cuid13793; 452894 (Cassette 120)
  - Side 1: Historical Materialism (2); Side 2: Philosophy (?), Undated; cuid13794; 452893 (Cassette 121)
  - Side 1: Historical Materialism / Reports from Students; Side 2: Remarks on Monopoly, Undated; cuid13795; 452892 (Cassette 122)
  - Historical Materialism, Feb 1975; cuid13796; 452891 (Cassette 123)
  - Historical Materialism, Feb 1975; cuid13797; 452890 (Cassette 124)
  - Historical Materialism (3), Jan 1976; cuid13798; 452889 (Cassette 125)
  - Historical Materialism, Aug 1976; cuid13799; 452888 (Cassette 126)
  - Historical Materialism - Side 1: Social History, Social Economy; Side 2: Origin of Species and Racism, Jan 1976; cuid13800; 452887 (Cassette 127)
  - Historical Materialism (Lecture and Student Reports), Aug 1976; cuid13801; 452886 (Cassette 128)
  - Historical Materialism (1) Slavery, Feudalism, Mar 1977; cuid13802; 452885 (Cassette 129)
  - Historical Materialism (2) Slavery, Feudalism, Mar 1977; cuid13803; 452884 (Cassette 130)
  - Historical Materialism (3) Slavery, Feudalism, Mar 1977; cuid13804; 452883 (Cassette 131)
  - Historical Materialism (1) National School, Mar 1977; cuid13805; 452882 (Cassette 132)
  - Historical Materialism (2) National School, Mar 1977; cuid13806; 452881 (Cassette 133)
  - Historical Materialism (3) National School, Mar 1977; cuid13807; 452880 (Cassette 134)
  - Historical Materialism, Jul 1978; cuid13808; 452879 (Cassette 135)
  - Historical Materialism, Jul 1978; cuid13809; 452878 (Cassette 136)
  - Side 1: Historical Materialism / Discussion; Side 2: Historical Materialism, Feb 1978; cuid13810; 452877 (Cassette 137)
  - Side 1: Historical Materialism; Side 2: Report, Discussion, Feb 1978; cuid13811; 452876 (Cassette 138)
  - Historical Materialism / Discussion, Feb 1978; cuid13812; 452875 (Cassette 139)
  - Side 1: Historical Overview of Russian History; Side 2: Panel: New Stage of USSR WBAI, Oct 1981; cuid13813; 452874 (Cassette 140)
  - History of the CPUSA: Policy on African-American Equality, 1988; cuid13814; 452873 (Cassette 141)
  - History of the Struggle in the South, Aug 1974; cuid13815; 452872 (Cassette 142)
  - Jewish Commission, Undated; cuid13816; 452871 (Cassette 143)
  - The Joel CaseStudents' Testimony + Response, 1977; cuid13817; 452870 (Cassette 144)
  - Side 1: Ideology, Capitalism; Side 2: Capitalism, National School, Mar 1977; cuid13818; 452869 (Cassette 145)
  - Ideological Discussion, Jun 1989; cuid13819; 452868 (Cassette 146)
  - Imperialism, Undated; cuid13820; 452867 (Cassette 147)
  - Imperialism (1, 2-3), Undated; cuid13821; 452866 (Cassette 148)
  - Imperialism (2-3, 4), Undated; cuid13822; 452865 (Cassette 149)
  - Imperialism (3-4), Undated; cuid13823; 452864 (Cassette 150)
  - Imperialism, 1973; cuid13824; 452863 (Cassette 151)
  - Imperialism, Aug 1974; cuid13825; 452862 (Cassette 152)
  - Imperialism, Mar 1978; cuid13826; 452861 (Cassette 153)
  - Side 1: Imperialism; Side 2: Political Economy / Coroup Reports, Jul 1978; cuid13827; 452860 (Cassette 154)
  - India, USSR and World Peace / On Polish CrisisD.W. Forum, NYC, Nov 1980; cuid13828; 452859 (Cassette 155)
  - Inflation (2-3), Undated; cuid13829; 452858 (Cassette 156)
  - The Internationale, Undated; cuid13830; 452857 (Cassette 157)
  - Karl Marx Centennial ConferenceSpeech by J. Jackson, Mar 1983; cuid13831; 452856 (Cassette 158)
  - Left Wing Communism, Aug 1977; cuid13832; 452855 (Cassette 159)
  - Left Wing Communism, Aug 1977; cuid13833; 452854 (Cassette 160)
  - Left Wing Communism and Internationalism (3), Aug 1977; cuid13834; 452853 (Cassette 161)
  - Lenin and the Revolutionary Party, Jun 1974; cuid13835; 452852 (Cassette 162)
  - Lenin, Tribute to, Undated; cuid13836; 452851 (Cassette 163)
  - Leninist Strategy and Tactics, Feb 1977; cuid13837; 452850 (Cassette 164)
  - Line of March: C.C. Meeting, Dec 1984; cuid13838; 452849 (Cassette 165)
  - Line of the March, Dec 1984; cuid13839; 452848 (Cassette 166)
  - Side 1: Freedomways - Nirma, Lollie, Geroge D.; Side 2: Maoism - Jackson J., Undated; cuid13840; 452847 (Cassette 167)
  - Maoism (2), Dec 1975; cuid13841; 452846 (Cassette 168)
  - Maoism (3), Dec 1975; cuid13842; 452845 (Cassette 169)
  - Side 1: Maoism; Side 2: Falsifiers of Marxism (with Victor Perlo), Dec 1975; cuid13843; 452844 (Cassette 170)
  - Maoism, Jan 1976; cuid13844; 452843 (Cassette 171)
  - Maoism, 1977; cuid13845; 452842 (Cassette 172)
  - Side 1: Martin Luther King (Hoyen, R.; Ronelle); Martin Luther King (Jackson, J.) Morality (Newcomer, S.), Undated; cuid13846; 452841 (Cassette 173)
  - On Martin Luther King, Jan 1976; cuid13847; 452840 (Cassette 174)
  - Materialism / Dialectics, Jul 1977; cuid13848; 452839 (Cassette 175)
  - Middle East, Speech onMass Rally in N.Y. versus Israel War on Palestinians, Oct 1982; cuid13849; 452838 (Cassette 176)
  - Side 1: Moral Question; Side 2: Jewish Question by Spector, Danny, Apr 1978; cuid13850; 452837 (Cassette 177)
  - Side 1: Moral Role; Side 2: Gay Question 3/28, Undated; cuid13851; 452836 (Cassette 178)
  - Side 1: Morality - Jackson, J. 3/28; Side 2: Mitchell, C. 3/29, Undated; cuid13852; 452835 (Cassette 179)
  - Morality, Mar 1978; cuid13853; 452834 (Cassette 180)
  - Morality and Revolution, Mar 1978; cuid13854; 452833 (Cassette 181)
  - Side 1: Morality (James Jackson); Political Economy (Hy Lumer); Side 2: Political Economy, Inflation (Hy Lumer), Dec 1975; cuid13855; 452832 (Cassette 182)
  - Side 1: National Question; Side 2: Trade Union, Undated; cuid13856; 452831 (Cassette 183)
  - National Question (1-2) (End of Maoism), Undated; cuid13857; 452830 (Cassette 184)
  - National Question (2), Undated; cuid13858; 452829 (Cassette 185)
  - National Question (3-4), Undated; cuid13859; 452828 (Cassette 186)
  - National Question (5-6), Undated; cuid13860; 452827 (Cassette 187)
  - Side 1: National Question (James Jackson); Side 2: Racism (Sylvia Newcombe), Mar 3, 1975-Mar 4, 1975; cuid13861; 452826 (Cassette 188)
  - National Question Party School, Mar 1975; cuid13862; 452825 (Cassette 189)
  - National Question (2) Party School, Mar 1975; cuid13863; 452824 (Cassette 190)
  - National Question, Dec 1975; cuid13864; 452823 (Cassette 191)
  - National Question (2), Dec 1975; cuid13865; 452822 (Cassette 192)
  - National Question (3), Dec 1975; cuid13866; 452821 (Cassette 193)
  - Side 1: National Question (4); Side 2: Political Economy, Dec 12, 1975-Dec 14, 1975; cuid13867; 452820 (Cassette 194)
  - National Question, Dec 1975; cuid13868; 452819 (Cassette 195)
  - National Question (Puerto Ricans, Chicanos, Indians, Asians), Dec 1975; cuid13869; 452818 (Cassette 196)
  - National Question, Feb 1976; cuid13870; 452817 (Cassette 197)
  - National Question (1), Jul 1976; cuid13871; 452816 (Cassette 198)
  - National Question (3), Mar 1977; cuid13872; 452815 (Cassette 199)
  - National Question / Political Economy Review, Dec 1977; cuid13873; 452814 (Cassette 200)
  - National Question (3), Jan 1979; cuid13874; 452813 (Cassette 201)
  - The Party, Undated; cuid13875; 452812 (Cassette 202)